I couldn't say goodbye
Ienai ienai sayonara nante
even though I love you so much
Konna ni daisuki na no ni
You said we should break up
Mou wakareyou to
Kimi no koe ga kikoeta shunkan
and when I heard that
my world turned white in an instant
Mou masshiro ni natte
Karadajuu ni hashitta hibana
and sparks danced in my vision
Is forgetting you what I need
Kimi no koto wo wasureru koto ga
Mae ni susundeku koto na no?
to move on?
I could cry now, I don't understand
Wakaranai yo nakete kuru yo
Let's live in the moment, only in the moment
Seiippai meiippai ima wo ikiyou
We lived like that until now, too, I guess
Sou yatte ikite kita kedo
I couldn't say goodbye
Ienai ienai sayonara nante
Konna ni daisuki na no ni
even though I love you so much
（滝川吉野・心の声）≪真広に
言わなくちゃいけないことがある≫
There's something I have to tell Mahiro.
We interrupt our regularly scheduled programming to bring you this special news bulletin.
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]　予定を変更して報道特別番組を
お送りしております。→
News Bulletin
____________
________
Another "Mage"
A new mage appears!
What is her motive?
今日未明　新たな魔法使いが
再び現れました。
Earlier today, the new mage appeared again.
（不破真広）≪吉野から
聞かなきゃいけないことがある≫
There's something I have to ask Yoshino.
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]（キャスター）本日正午過ぎ
絶園の魔法使いと共に　今回も→
The new mage appeared alongside the mage of Exodus again today, just past noon.
新たな魔法使いが現れました。
バシン！
ガン！
ガキッ！
≪約束した以上は→
I promised,
次に会うときには
言わなきゃならない≫
so I have to tell him the next time I see him.
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]（キャスター）
ただいま入りました情報です。→
This just in.
A mysterious flying fruit has been spotted in the sky near Akaiyama.
赤城山上空で
謎の巨大な果実が目撃され→
そこには　絶園の魔法使いと→
The mage of Exodus was seen there with the new mage as well.
新たな魔法使いの姿も
あったとのことです。→
この果実は　以前からも
目撃情報が寄せられており…。
Previously, we received information that similar fruits were sighted...
The New Mage Is the "Dancing Princess"
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]　政府の通達に従い　以後→
Following a government notice,
we will now refer to the new mage
新たな魔法使いを
舞姫と呼称します。→
as the "Dancing Princess."
一連の事件に関し
警察および　国防軍は→
Regarding these incidents, the police and the military
静観の姿勢を崩さず→
continue to maintain their silence,
関係各省庁への批判が
相次いでいます。
and the government faces mounting criticism.
≪吉野は…≫
Yoshino.
（回想）((お前に　愛花ちゃんの彼氏が
誰だったか教えてやる))
I'll tell you the identity of Aika's boyfriend.
≪真広は…≫
Mahiro,
Episode 19
The Object of Desire
（吉野・真広）
≪覚えているだろうか≫
I wonder if you remember.
（山本）はぁ…　あの姫様は
なんちゅうことをしてくれたんや。
What the hell did that princess do?
（早河）おかげで　政府も
はじまりの樹破壊案には懐疑的だ。
Thanks to her, the government is now wary of the plan to destroy the Tree of Genesis.
Oh well. I guess it's time to regroup with the princess.
（山本）いいかげん　あのお姫様とは
合流したいところね。
（早河）とはいえ
ネックは　あの二人だな。
But the bigger problem is those two...
彼は戻ったのか？
Has he come back yet?
（山本）あれから　一度も。
携帯も置いてっちゃったし。
No, not even once,
though he even left his cell phone.
問題ばかり増えていくな。
（山本）ほんと　これ以上…。
It seems like one problem after another.
Tell me about it. One more and—
パキーン！
キキーーッ！（ブレーキ音）
An attack?!
襲撃か!?
（哲馬）
張っていた結界が吹き飛んだ。→
We crashed through a barrier,
though you might as well call it an attack.
襲撃といえば襲撃だが…。
（山本）また問題が増えたわ。
And the problems just keep piling up...
≪吉野に会って→
When I see Yoshino
愛花の彼氏が誰だったか聞いて
俺は　どうする？≫
and ask him about Aika's boyfriend, what am I going to do?
≪どうしたいんだ？≫
What do I want to do?
((おい　愛花　お前は　病弱な
深窓の令嬢みたいな外見して→
Hey, Aika,
how come you look like a frail, sheltered "damsel"
どうして　そう
格好も生活態度も雑なんだ？))
but act and dress like a slob?
That's because I'm neither frail nor sheltered.
（愛花）((それは　中身が　病弱な
深窓の令嬢ではないからですよ))
Besides, Mahiro,
（愛花）((真広こそ
妹に自分の理想を→
trying to impose your ideals onto your sister is in rather bad taste.
押しつけようなんて
とんだ悪趣味ですね))
((はぁ…　お前の今の姿の方が
趣味悪いぞ))
Well, the way you're sitting now is in even worse taste.
((こういう私を認められたら→
When you can accept me the way I am,
真広も一人前ですよ))
((あっ…))
you'll be a real adult.
This, coming from a kid in junior high.
((中学生が生意気なこと言うな))
((その調子じゃ　お前→
At this rate,
I doubt you'll find yourself a boyfriend any time soon.
当分　彼氏はできそうにねぇな))
（店主）はい　小倉あんが３つに
クリームが３つ→
All right, three with red-bean paste, three with cream,
あと　豆乳クリームが２つね。
どうも。
and two with soy cream.
Thanks.
（葉風）なるほど。
はじまりの樹超兵器説に加えて→
I see.
So on top of the theory that
the Tree of Genesis is a superweapon,
吉野に絶園の魔法使い疑惑…　か。
there are allegations that Yoshino is the mage of Exodus.
You don't look surprised.
（山本）驚かないのね。
（葉風）言いたいことは分かるが→
I understand what you mean to say,
私が
吉野に操られているとしたら→
but if Yoshino were really controlling me,
わざわざ
羽村を鍛えてやったりはせんよ。
I wouldn't bother training Hanemura.
（山本）はぁ…　それなんだけど→
Speaking of...
しばらく
舞姫は休んでくれない？→
Couldn't you put off the "Dancing Princess" act for a bit?
Hanemura is worn out.
羽村君　ボロボロだから。
と言っても…。
Then again...
ドカッ！
（羽村）うわっ！
（潤一郎）
考えるんじゃない。　感じるんだ。
Don't think.
Feel!
（山本）潤一郎君に　ジムで
鍛え直されてるみたいだけど。
Apparently, Junichiro's been training him in the gym.
（葉風）さすがの潤兄さんも
尻に火がついたか。
So even Jun is feeling somewhat motivated now.
（早河）
どこぞの姫君のおかげですよ。
All thanks to a certain princess we know.
（葉風）まあ　そう言うな。→
Come on. Don't be like that.
果実を飛ばす協力も
したではないか。
I even helped you get a fruit to fly.
左門殿は　果実を飛ばす準備に
１年もかかったというのに…。
To think it took Mr. Samon an entire year to do that...
だから　私は姫様なのだよ　哲馬。
That's why I'm the princess, Tetsuma.
残る果実は一つだ。
There's one fruit left.
As long as the Tree of Exodus doesn't absorb it,
それを
絶園の樹に吸収させんかぎり→
樹は　完全復活せんし
羽村の力も完全になるまい。→
it cannot fully revive,
and Hanemura's power won't reach full strength.
さて　多忙の早河を
つきあわせるのも忍びない。→
Now, then...
There's no further reason to detain Hayakawa.
場所を変えるか　フロイライン。
（山本）えっ？
Let's change our venue, Fräulein.
What?
（葉風）貴様の説を
ゆっくり聞きたいのでな。
I'd like to hear your theory in much greater detail.
喜んで。
My pleasure.
（葉風）惑星が　ほかの惑星に
侵略する能力を奪うための→
One planet sent out weapons that destroy civilizations
to prevent other planets from becoming possible threats?
文明破壊兵器か…。
Right.
（山本）そう　「文明破壊機」とでも
名付けましょうか。→
How about we just call it the "Civilization Blaster"?
An unmanned weapon, programmed to destroy civilization once it has reached a certain point;
文明が　ある段階に達すれば
破壊するよう→
プログラムされた無人兵器。→
A superweapon scattered across the universe to ensure that extraterrestrial lifeforms
その生命体が生まれた星だけで
穏やかに暮らすため→
will remain confined to their home planets.
宇宙にばらまかれた超兵器。→
That weapon is
それに対して付けられた名が→
the Tree of Genesis,
はじまりの樹。→
あなたの神様。
your god.
（山本）鎖部一族も
兵器システムの一環でしょうね。→
I'm sure that the Kusaribe clan
is a part of this weapon system too.
一族が供物として捧げる
文明の産物をサンプルに→
The clan provides samples of civilization as sacrifices to the Tree,
which can determine how advanced the civilization has become.
その文明レベルを判断している…
とか。
ふっ　あまりに想像を外れた話だ。
It sounds pretty far-fetched to me.
我々が使うのは魔法だぞ。
What we use is magic,
the power of nature that governs all logic.
理を統べる超自然の力だぞ。→
To portray that as an alien weapon is absu—
それを　異星人の兵器だとするのは
いくらなんでも…。
あまりに進んだ科学は
魔法と区別がつかない。
Once science evolves past a certain point,
it's hard to distinguish it from magic.
私たちが魔法と呼び　恐れる力は→
So how can you be sure that the power we fear as "magic"
未知の科学の産物でないと
どうして言える？
isn't just the product of a science we don't understand?
では　絶園の樹は　どう説明する？
Then how do you explain the Tree of Exodus?
はじまりの樹の目的を妨害し
破壊する樹が→
Why would a Tree that can interfere and destroy the Tree of Genesis
なぜ　同じ惑星に存在するのだ？
（山本）そうね→
exist on the same planet?
Good point.
It could be that the two Trees were designed as one,
二つの樹は　最初から
一つのものとしてデザインされ→
同時に地球に現れたとした方が
むしろ自然かもね。
and both appeared on the planet simultaneously.
But that would make your
"ultimate weapon" theory rather unlikely.
そうすると　超兵器説は
無理筋ということになるが。
発想の方向性としては
正しいと思う。→
Well, I still think I'm on the right track,
あれが　どこかの何かが
邪な意思を持って→
believing that thing out there was sent to our planet
私たちの世界に
侵入させたものだってことは。
by someone or something with malicious intent.
お土産　冷めちゃったな。
It's gotten all cold.
（葉風）貴様の説
はじまりの姫君としては→
As the Princess of Genesis,
I must say I have mixed feelings regarding your theory,
複雑な気分だが　同感ではある。
but I agree with the basic premise.
それでも今
はじまりの樹は→
Nevertheless,
the Tree of Genesis lets me to control it, at least for now.
曲がりなりにも
私の制御を受けている。
If it has malicious intent,
邪悪な意思があるにせよ
なぜ　そこに住む者によって→
why allow someone on the target planet to control it?
制御が
可能にされているのか…→
That makes no sense.
それも腑に落ちんしな。
≪ひとまず　お姫様は　冷静に
物を見られているようね≫
Looks like the princess is still capable of thinking objectively.
（山本）で　吉野君とは
うまくいってるの？
So, are things going well with Yoshino?
（葉風）どうして　いきなり
そういう話になるのだ。
How did we get to talking about that?
If the Tree of Genesis is an aggressor we must defeat,
もし　はじまりの樹が
倒すべき侵略者なら→
その姫宮である
あなたを殺すのは→
the one who may try to kill that aggressor's princess
絶園の魔法使いである→
could very well be Yoshino,
assuming he is the true mage of Exodus.
吉野君になるかも
しれないじゃない。
There's no definite proof that it's Yoshino,
まだ吉野だという確証はない。
だが　そうだな→
but you do have a point.
それはそれで　悪くない。
In and of itself, that wouldn't be so bad.
≪ここのところは要注意か≫
I guess we still need to be on alert...
≪愛ゆえに　この姫様は→
Who knows what this princess could do in the name of love?
最後の最後で
何をやらかすかしれない≫
≪ほれた男のために死ぬって→
Still, to be willing to die for the man she loves is kind of sweet.
結構　甘美だからね≫
（葉風）そうだ　フロイライン。→
Fräulein, I'd like to make a request.
ひとつ　頼まれてほしいのだが。
（山本）ん？
Hmm?
Could you ask that Samon's barrel
富士山麓から　左門の樽と→
and Mahiro's wooden doll be retrieved from Mt. Fuji?
真広が使用していた
木彫りの人形を回収するよう→
指示してもらえないか？
（山本）樽と人形？
The barrel and the doll?
≪何も答えない墓に
何を願っている？≫
What's there to ask of an unresponsive grave?
≪何を祈っている？≫
What's there to pray for?
Saying anything after someone's death is too little, too late.
≪死んでから何を言っても
全部　手遅れだろ≫
≪墓に参って
何を慰められたがってる？≫
What kind of comfort can you get from a grave?
≪理屈に合いやしねぇ≫
It makes no sense.
≪そういや　吉野も…≫
Now that I think about it, Yoshino...
≪やっぱり　俺には場違いだな≫
I guess this was a mistake after all.
I thought that if I came here, I might change my mind.
≪こういう所に来れば　気分も
少しは変わると思ったが…≫
≪俺は
どう変わることを望んだ？≫
What kind of change was I hoping for?
帰るか。
こんな所で　知った顔にでも…。
Guess I'll head back.
It's not like I'll run into anyone I—
なんで　こんな所にいるんだ？
What are you doing here?
いやいや
それは　こっちのセリフだって。
That's what I should be saying.
自分の家の墓参りも
ろくにしなかったお前が→
You rarely even visited the family grave, so why are you here?
どうして…。
散歩だ　散歩。　ほかに意味はねぇ。
I'm taking a walk.
That's all.
Well? Why are you here?
で　なんで　お前は　ここにいる？
みんな　僕らに気を遣ってか→
I haven't had a chance to see you again,
別行動のままになってるからさ→
since everyone's been giving us time apart.
さすがに悪いから
僕から　お前に会いに→
I felt bad, so I thought I'd buy these
手土産も買って
近くまで来たんだけど…。
and try to find you on my own,
よりによって　こんなとこで
いきなり会うなんてなぁ。
but to think I'd end up running into you here...
俺も　お前も　うかつだな。
We've both been pretty careless.
なんで気付かなかったんだか。
ん？
How could we not have noticed it?
「ハムレット」じゃ
妹の死後　その兄と　その恋人は→
In Hamlet, after the younger sister dies,
墓地で　ばったり
再会するじゃねぇか。
her brother and her boyfriend reunite in a graveyard.
約束だ。
えっ？
You promised.
愛花の彼氏のこと聞かせろよ。
Let's talk about Aika's boyfriend,
ついでに　お前の彼女のことも。
and, while we're at it, about your girlfriend too,
話す手間は変わらないだろ？
since that shouldn't require any extra effort.
そうだな。　まったく変わらない。
You're right.
It won't.
This is disgusting. It's all cold...
まずいな。
すっかり冷めてるじゃねぇか。
こっち食べるか？
どっちにしても冷めてるだろ。
Want this one?
All of them are cold anyway.
というわけで→
So anyway,
I'm Aika's boyfriend.
僕が愛花ちゃんの彼氏なんだよ。
んぐっ！
いきなり
「というわけで」で済ますなよ。
Don't say it so bluntly.
最初から　きっちり説明しろ。
Start from the beginning.
説明していいのか？
あっ？
You sure you're okay with that?
Huh?
僕と愛花ちゃんが
いつから　つきあって→
Explaining how Aika and I began dating,
どこに　デートに行って→
where we went on dates,
when we started holding hands,
どこから手をつなぐようになって
そして→
and even when we first kissed.
いつごろ
キスをするようになったか…。
You kissed?!
キスしたのか!?
あ…　愛花とキスしやがったのか!?
Y-You k-kissed Aika?
What the hell did you do to my Aika?
俺の愛花に何してやがんだ！
お前のじゃないって。
She didn't belong to you.
お前のでもないだろ！
いや→
She wasn't yours either!
Well...
In this case, I'd say she actually was mine.
この場合
「僕の」という方が正しくないか？
だって僕は　正真正銘→
I mean, after all, I was her one and only boyfriend.
愛花ちゃんの彼氏なんだから。
俺に隠れて
こそこそ　つきあってたくせに→
You were the one seeing her behind my back,
ここへきて開き直りやがって…。
まあ→
and yet, you have the nerve to talk to me like that.
Well,
半殺しにされる覚悟で
来たわけだから。
I did come here expecting you to beat me to a pulp.
ほんとに
お前が愛花の彼氏なんだよな。
Then you really are Aika's boyfriend.
彼氏なんだよ。
I am.
それで　僕を殴らないのか？
So then, you aren't going to hit me?
殴られるようなことしたのか？
Is there a reason I should?
ほら　兄であるお前に隠れて→
Well...
I was seeing Aika behind your back,
愛花ちゃんと
つきあってたわけだし。
and you're her brother.
So?
別に　兄だからって
報告の義務はねぇよ。
You weren't required to tell me just because I'm her brother.
But it was Aika.
でも　愛花ちゃんだぞ？
じゃあ　愛花の弱み握って→
Well, did you do something like uncover
her weakness to force her to go out with you?
無理やりつきあってたとかなのか？
いや→
No.
逆に
弱み握られてた気分だったけど。
If anything, she knew my weakness.
なら
俺が　お前を殴る理由はねぇよ。
Then, there's no reason I should hit you.
ん？
それは　理屈に合わねぇ。
It would make no sense.
俺は　愛花にとって
何者でもなかったんだからな。
I wasn't really anyone to Aika anyway.
俺は
愛花と友達だったわけでもねぇ。
I wasn't friends with her
いい兄だったこともねぇ。
or a good brother.
兄であることすら
まともに認めたこともねぇ。
I never even admitted to being her brother.
ましてや　恋人でもなければ
好きだと言ったこともねぇ。
We weren't lovers,
and I never told her I liked her.
I didn't tell Aika anything.
俺は　何も　愛花に伝えてないんだ。
好きかどうかってのも→
Until recently, I hadn't even realized that I liked her.
つい最近まで
自覚すらしてなかった。
そんな自覚すらなかったんだ。
I couldn't even figure that out.
So what gives me the right to hit the one Aika liked and was dating?
その俺が　愛花が好きで
つきあってたヤツを→
なんで殴る資格がある？
It doesn't make sense.
理屈に合わねぇ。　全然合わねぇよ。
None at all.
はぁ…　不合理すぎる。
It's absurd.
あの愛花にも好きな男がいて→
If Aika actually liked someone
そいつと
楽しく過ごせていたなら→
and she was happy being with him,
喜んでやるのが筋だろ。
I should be happy for her,
especially since it was you.
それが　お前なら　なおさらだ。
≪真広は　強いな≫
You're strong, Mahiro...
愛花は　いい子だったろ？
Aika was a good person, wasn't she?
Well, her personality was pretty horrible.
性格は悪かったけどね。
いい子だったろ!?
She was a good person, right?
She had a pretty small rack though.
胸は小さかったけどね。
ちっ…。
Being her boyfriend doesn't mean you get to say whatever you want.
彼氏だからって
何を言ってもいいわけじゃねぇぞ。
そういや
お前が　富士で異常なくらい→
By the way, when you went all out for Hakaze at Mt. Fuji,
葉風に肩入れしたの
愛花が理由か？
was it because of Aika?
あそこで何もしなかったら→
I thought that if I did nothing,
愛花ちゃんの死が
悲劇のためのものになると思った。
Aika's death would have been used only for tragedy.
だから　それを止めようと思った。
That's why I tried to stop it.
今も
そのために動いてるつもりだよ。
Even now, I believe that I am acting for that reason.
お前が　愛花ちゃんの復讐のために
何をしようとかまわない。
I don't care what you do to get revenge for Aika's death,
でも　僕は　せめて
愛花ちゃんの死によって→
but at the very least, I want to help save the world with her death.
世界が救われたと思える
最後にしてみせる。
「テンペスト」…　か。
知っているのか？
The Tempest, huh?
You know it?
何しろ　俺は　愛花の兄だからな。
Well, I am Aika's brother.
俺は
愛花を殺したヤツを許す気はねぇ。
I have no intention of forgiving Aika's killer,
たとえ
それで　悲劇で終わるとしてもだ。
not even if it ends in tragedy.
はぁ…　場合によっては
僕らは敵同士か？
So depending on how things pan out, we may become enemies.
It's not like I have an obligation to get along with her boyfriend.
愛花の彼氏と
仲よくする義務もねぇだろ。
しかし　吉野→
But Yoshino,
お前　よく愛花とつきあってたのを
隠してられたな。
I'm surprised you were able to hide dating Aika.
愛花ちゃんが
しっかりしてたからね。
Well, Aika was on top of it.
No, I mean after she died.
違うだろ。　愛花が死んでからだ。
ああ…。
Well, I managed somehow.
まあ　なんとかね。
ふん。
≪無駄に強ぇヤツだよ≫
You're needlessly strong.
真広こそ　よく僕を信用できるな。
I'm surprised you can still trust me, Mahiro.
何がだ？
愛花ちゃんが死んだあとも→
With what?
Since I continued to lead a normal life even after her death,
変わらず
平然と暮らしてきた僕を→
本気で愛花ちゃんと
つきあっていたかって→
I could understand if you doubted that I was dating her.
疑いそうなものだけど。
お前が泣くも悲しむも→
I know that you aren't the type
俺の前ではしねぇヤツってのは
知ってる。
who'd cry or be sad in front of me,
俺も　お前の前では
泣きも　わめきも　してないだろ。
just like I wouldn't be that way in front of you.
Have you cried in front of someone else?
僕の前以外じゃ
泣いたりしたのか？
（愛花）
((こういう私を認められたら→
When you can accept me the way I am,
you'll be a real adult.
真広も一人前ですよ))
((あっ…))
This, coming from a kid in junior high.
((中学生が生意気なこと言うな))
((その調子じゃ　お前→
At this rate,
当分　彼氏はできそうにねぇな))
I doubt you'll find yourself a boyfriend any time soon.
まったく…。
Damn...
俺は　本当に　本当に→
I must really,
愛花のことが好きなんだな…。
really love Aika.
やっぱり　１発くらい
僕のこと殴っとくか？
Are you sure you don't want to hit me, at least once?
If I were going to hit you, it wouldn't be just once.
殴るとしたら　１発で済まねぇよ。
[TEL]
（左門）私だ。
It is I.
[TEL]（夏村）
申し訳ありません　夏村です。
Pardon me, sir. It's Natsumura.
What's the matter? Is there a problem?
（左門）
どうした。　問題が起こったか？
Well, not quite...
[TEL]（夏村）問題といいますか…。
（左門）なんだ？
Then what?
Fuwa Mahiro has returned to the apartment with Takigawa Yoshino.
[TEL]（夏村）
今　不破真広と滝川吉野が→
一緒に
マンションに戻ってきました。
（左門）何ぃ!?
ん？
What?!
A reconciliation?
（左門）わ…　和解!?
[TEL]（夏村）はい　妹の件についても→
Yes.
They appear to have settled their dispute over Fuwa Mahiro's sister.
和解が成立したようで。
（左門）姫様は　そこにいるのか？
Is the princess there?
[TEL]（夏村）あっ　いえ
先ほど　お知らせしたところ→
She is not.
When I informed her of the matter earlier, she seemed rather panicked.
ひどく慌てていらして…。
（左門）分かった。→
Very well. I shall return tomorrow.
私も　明日　戻る。
何かあったら連絡をくれ。
Should anything happen, inform me immediately.
≪本来なら　二人の和解は
喜ぶべきことなのだが…≫
Under normal circumstances, their reconciliation would be a cause for joy.
≪一体　どうなっている？≫
But what in the world is going on?
≪私は　いつまで
こんなことに悩まされるのだ…≫
How much longer must I deal with such things?
（葉風）真広！
Mahiro!
私の吉野に
何もしなかったろうな!?
You didn't dare do anything to my Yoshino, did you?!
No, I didn't.
してねぇよ。　あと　いつから
吉野は　お前のものになったんだ？
And since when is Yoshino yours?
（葉風）言葉のあやだ。
それ　間違った使い方してねぇか？
It's a play on words!
I don't think you're using the right expression.
（葉風）
なんだ？　部屋の模様替えか。
What? You're redecorating?
２人　余計に増えたからな。
Well, we need room for two more people now.
Is this becoming a girls-only bedroom?
この部屋は　女子専用の寝室に？
なんなら
私と吉野専用の寝室でもいいぞ！
If anything, it could be our bedroom, Yoshino!
なんだ？　まさか
愛花に義理立てしてるのか？
What? Are you trying to be faithful to Aika?
If I weren't, you'd be pissed.
しなかったら　お前　怒るだろ？
まあ　それで　お前を殴っても
理屈には合うだろうな。
Well, it would give me a reason to hit you.
If you're going to get hit anyway,
殴られるくらいで済むなら
私に手を出せ　吉野。
you should totally play with me, Yoshino.
存外　不破愛花より
柔らかくてたまらんかもしれんぞ。
Maybe I'll even surprise you by being more cuddly and irresistible than Fuwa Aika.
確かに　愛花ちゃんは
骨っぽくて固かったですけどね。
Well, Aika was kind of scrawny and hard,
くっ…。
腕も　ゴボウみたいに細くて…。
and her arms were as stringy as carrots.
おい　吉野！
（羽村）ただいま。　あっ。
Yoshino!
We're home—
Don't compare my sister to a vegetable!
人の妹を　根菜で例えるな！
いや　悪気はなかったんだよ。
How else could I have put it?!
Don't interfere, Mahiro!
（葉風）真広　邪魔をするな！
これでよかったのか？
さあな。
Are you all right with how things ended up?
I guess.
お前こそ　これでいいのかよ？
What about you? Are you okay with everything?
吉野は
たぶん　愛花しか見てねぇぞ。
Yoshino probably has feelings only for Aika.
（葉風）この世には
かなわぬ恋の方が多いものだ。→
In this world, unrequited love is far too common.
高望みはせんよ。
I won't get my hopes up.
それに
私は　自身の生まれと行いの→
Not to mention,
I must take responsibility for who I am and for my actions.
責任を取らねばならん。
By the way,
そういや　お前
愛花を殺した犯人を→
I heard that you thought of a way to find Aika's killer.
見つける手を
考えついたらしいじゃねぇか。
Yes.
うまくいけば
真実を目にすることができよう。
If all goes well, we should finally find out the truth.
しかし　それが　どんなものであれ
悲劇は止めねばならん。
But no matter the outcome, we must put an end to the tragedy.
For Yoshino's sake?
吉野のためにか？
ほかに何がある？
Why else?
Even if you don't mean it, you should say, "For the world's sake."
そこは　うそでも
世界のためと言っとけ。
左門が泣くぞ。
貴様が言うな。
You'd make Samon cry.
You're one to talk.
世界のためなどより→
When you do something for the man you love instead of for the world,
ほれた男のための方が
迷わず　事を選べる。
it's easier to decide what must be done.
究極のところ　何かのためより→
Ultimately, it's better to do things for someone, rather than for something.
誰かのための方が強くあれるのだ。
（葉風）真広　頼むぞ。
I'm counting on you as well, Mahiro.
貴様も誰のための戦いか
見誤るなよ。
Don't forget who this battle is for.
俺は…。
I...
俺のためにしか動かねぇよ。
I only act for myself.
≫（山本）最強の魔法使い様が→
The invincible mage seems to be wearing a rather helpless expression.
なんとも
頼りない顔してるじゃないの。
みんな　信念に従って
行動してるのは分かります。
I know that everyone's acting on their feelings,
でも　何が正しいのか
分からなくなっちゃって。
but I can't tell right from wrong anymore.
（山本）そうね。
真広君　吉野君　葉風さん→
I know what you mean.
Mahiro, Yoshino, Miss Hakaze.
あの三人は強いけれど→
All three of them are strong,
彼らが未来に願うのは→
but what they want from the future
所詮　かなわない夢なのよ。→
is something that cannot come true.
失ったものに未練ばかり残し→
They remain attached to what was lost,
行き止まりに向かって走るだけ。
and keep running into dead ends.
死人に足をつかまれた子たちに
従うのが→
I wonder if it's the right thing to listen to those haunted by the past.
果たして正しいかしらね？
じゃあ　左門さんと早河さんは？
Then, what about Mr. Samon and Mr. Hayakawa?
あの二人は　なるべく
多くの人間が生き残る選択を→
They're doing their best to ensure the highest possible number of survivors,
しようとはしているけど→
but they also don't care how many lives must be sacrificed in the process.
そのためには　どんな犠牲が出ても
かまわないとも思ってる。→
そんな連中が正しいなんて→
Whether that's the right thing,
私は　とても言えないわ～。
笑い事じゃないですって。
I can't say for sure either.
This isn't something to laugh about.
（山本）そうね。
でも　それぞれの正義なんて→
True, but if you change perspectives, you can make a joke of anyone's sense of justice.
立場が変われば
ただの悪い冗談よ。
要は　君自身は
なんのために戦うか。→
What matters is what you want to fight for.
それだけ決めときなさい。
You have to decide on that for yourself.
（葉風）最後の果実を飛ばす前に
確かめねばならんことがある。→
Before we get the last fruit to fly,
there is something I need to confirm.
Who was it that killed Fuwa Aika?
一体
誰が不破愛花を殺したのか。→
あるいは
そこに　今の混乱した状況と→
At the same time,
I believe we'll discover the truth behind the two Trees,
and what caused the current confusion.
二つの大樹の
真実があるとも思える。
Therefore, I'm planning to return to the past,
（葉風）そこで
私は再び　過去に戻ろうと思う。
不破愛花の殺される前の時間にな。
to a time before Fuwa Aika was killed!
kimi no utatta hanauta ga
The song you hummed
boku no hanauta to kasanatta
and the song I hummed were the same
yoku aru koto kamoshirenai kedo
Maybe this is not so rare,
tokubetsu datte omoitainda
but I'd like to believe it's special
tokidoki fuan ni mo naru kara
Sometimes everyone feels anxious
tsui mata sagashite shimaundayo
and we wind up seeking it again
me ni mienai ito no youna
Like an invisible string,
futari wo tsuyoku tsunagi au mono
it is what connects us two
tatoe hoka no dare ga waratte mo
Even if others laugh about that,
boku wa tsuyoku shinjiteru kara
I believe it exists,
ima mo zutto zutto negatte iruyo
and so I keep on wishing even now
futari de iru mirai wo
for a future where we are together
mae wo muite aruite yuku yo
I will look ahead and walk
hitori kiri janai kara
because I am not alone
itsu no hi ka kimi to hora unmei datta ne tte
I hope we can one day laugh and say "Hey, it was destiny"
issho ni waraeru to ii na
Wouldn't that be nice?
I used a massage chair for the
first time, but it just tickled.
It's quite affordable,
so I highly recommend it.
Well, that's impressive.
Huh? How'd it lead to that?
Maybe you got dumped because
you don't understand women...
（葉風）初めて　マッサージ機
というものを使ってみたが→
くすぐったいだけだな。
What?
You're lying!
（愛花）
値段も手ごろで　おすすめです。
Indeed, it is a lie.
Episode 20
Whodunit (Who did it?)